This week, we're going to be talking about chunks, compact packages of information that
your mind can easily access.
We'll talk about how you can form chunks, how you can use them to improve your understanding
of and creativity with the material, and how chunks can help you do better on tests.
We'll also talk about illusions of competence in learning.
This is when you're using ineffective study methods that fool your mind into thinking
you're learning something, when you're mostly just wasting your time.
We'll cover what those less effective study methods are, and tell you what methods research
has shown will work better to help you in your studies.
Finally, we'll talk about something called overlearning, which can solidly ingrain information
in your mind, but also can be a little like digging deeper ruts as you might spin your
wheels ineffectively in learning.
You can make your study time more valuable by interleaving, providing intelligent variety
in your studies.
I'm Barbara Oakley.
Thanks for learning how to learn.